Original subtitles in Hungarian
by Krassimir Sevova
Translated & resynchronized
by titta to Addic7ed.com
Why didn't they ask...
- Sorry?
Why ...
didn't they ask... Evans?
Evans? Ask him what?
"Why didn't they ask Evans?"
Good morning, ma'am.
- Good morning. Thank you.
Jane! Dear ...
- Marjorie.
Oh! Goodness, is this Bobby?
Well ...
Say hello to Miss Marple.
- Hello, Miss Marple.
This was at the doorstep.
It looks rather important.
You don't have to go.
Why do you have to go, Bobby?
Oh Jane, dear, do come in.
Roberts, pour Miss Marple's tea.
We're in a bit of
a drama, I'm affraid.
The letter, you gave Bobby ...
- Yes?...
Oh! We've been rather upset recently.
Bobby found a body.
Gracious!
- On the cliff. A Mr...
Prichard.
- Prichard.
An accident, the police said, which is
why he doesn't have to go to the inquest.
Then this letter's come out of the blue,
and it's not even in the village,
but in Market Dorning, of all places.
- You've told them everything, haven't you?
- Yes!
Sorry.
- Really, Roberts!
Sorry, Jane, she's new, I'm affraid.
- Just came back from my honeymoon.
How lovely!
- That's enough, Roberts!
Better be off, then.
- Bobby. Bobby!
Bobby? Bobby Atfield!
Frankie. Frankie Derwent.
You came to mummy's dance at Derwent Hall.
We played "Persona". You can't remember?.
I think I scared you off.
- Did you?
Well, this is rather ghastly.
Let's go to first.
So, how's tricks?
Oh, you know. Oldies in the vestry,
usual kind of thing.
How are you?
- Wild.
Just off to town,
meeting up with Pongo.
You know Pongo? Pongo Slim,
Such a gas. You should come.
I've got an inquest, actually.
- Oh, well, I didn't know...
God, someone you know?
- Well ...
Someone I found, actually.
- Found?! Do tell.
All shut-up.
Certainly odd.
There's no sign of an inquest.
The letter says ...
- It's clearly a fake.
But it's perfectly obvious.
Whoever pushed him, knows you found him,
but doesn't know if he said anything.
So, just in case, just in case, they made
sure you didn't go to the inquest.
Then I need to tell the Police.
- What?
- About Evans.
- No!
-What?
- We'll do this ourselves.
But ... I need ...
- Ah, fine, tell them everything!
Scaredy-cat.
- All right.
- What?
Let's do it.
So, there was an inquest
really, Inspector?
And who identified him?
His cousin ...
Richard, who, sorry?
Trent! Oh, Dick ... Dicky Trent.
They were so close.
Like brothers. Poor Dickie.
I don't suppose you've got his address?...
I know not meant to, Inspector.
It's just that my mother ...
Lady Derwent, yes, would so love
to drop him a line.
"Why didn't they ask Evans?"
Pretty loaded last words, I must say.
Let's pop it in the post, sit back
and see what does our Mr. Trent.
Now that the inquest trick didn't work, I wonder
what little surprise he's up the sleeve this time?
Come on!
Would love to see this lad's face
when he reads it.
"Dear Mr. Trent, sorry
to miss you at the inquest.
Mr. Prichard said something to me before
he died, which I feel that I should tell you.
He said: "Why didn't they
ask Evans?"
Yours most faithful, Robert Atfield"
Bobby, darling! Is that you?
Remember the time you fell
off the orchard wall,
when you broke your arm?
Bobby!
- I can still see you,
tittering along the top of it
shouting "I'm the Dark Avenger!"
"I'm dancing with death".
It could've been a lot worse.
About 9, weren't you?
Bobby, darling!
You never told her.
Said I tripped on a wheelbarow.
- You're doing it again?
- What?
Dancing with death.
- Quite good, aren't you?
- Thanks.
Any news from Trent, anything?
- No, nothing.
Damn! It could be a good sign, though.
Can be working on next move.
Frankie?
- What?
You know Miss Marple?
- Who?
- Well ...
- What's that old biddy up to?
I do so love the sea air. Don't you?
Hello.
- Any news from Mr. Trent?
- Sorry?
I was just wondering how
poor Mr. Prichard got here.
Prichard?
That's what I was trying to tell you.
What an enchanting lain!
I can't believe you told her,
a senile woman.
- She's not, actually.
- Com'on, keep up!
Well...
Could be our Mr. Prichard's.
Well, it could be anybody's.
From London. Mayfair.
Lovely view of your house, Bobby.
Reminds me of a film I saw
during the war.
These "comandos" in Crete stole a German
General's car with a coat hanger.
Is that the time? Marjorie
is expecting me for the 11's service.
Tough where they found a wire
coat hanger on a Cretan hillside,
I have no idea.
Yes!
- Oh! Anything of interest?
- Actually, yes.
Nothing much. Just an old pipe and some tobacco.
- And an hotel key.
May I?
Look, He's marked somewhere.
Castle Savage.
- That's miles from here.
- Castle Savage, I seem to recall...
Right, thanks for your help, Miss Marple.
You've been maravelous. Coming, Bobby?
- Right.
- Ah, bugger!
Bloody dinner parties.
Bloody mothers!
You could come!
- Me?
Well ...
- No. Don't worry.
Probably organized some...
man for me, anyway.
Pongo or someone.
- Probably.
If you change your mind...
- Anyway... better be going.
- Right.
... do that
sublime martini.
Or so I hear.
... very funny, we actually should.
Bye-bye, darling.
- Bye-bye.
My hero!
We caught him, Miss Marple!
- Caught who, dear?
Trent, of course. He tried to
wipe up Bobby.
He got our letter with Prichard's last words
and they're obviously highly incriminating.
Oh, poor darling. Is it terribly painful?
- A bit.
Right, com'on.
- What?
- Going to Castle Savage.
- Castle Savage. Why?
Prichard ringed it on the map. He was
obviously going there, or been there, something.
Maybe Trent will be there, or Evans.
And, guess what,
daddy knows Jack Savage.
The man who owns castle Savage.
Has an enormous tea empire
in China or somewhere.
Bad apple, apparently.
Anyway, he's dead.
And really sudden, too.
Heart attack, so they say, 6 months ago.
This is such a luck! Two dead bodies,
and we didn't even get started.
- No.
- What?
It's not a luck.
Someone tried to kill me.
Which is the prove we need--.
- Wait.
Wait? I don't wait.
- Go on your own, then.
Right. If that's what you want,
I will.
Fine hero you turned out to be.
She can do what she wants.
I don't care!
Go with bloody riddles.
- Quite, dear.
(Castle Savage)
Sorry, seems I ...
I got you, Ma'am.
You're alright.
This way.
I got you.
- Sorry.
Here
Will you be alright?
You're safe, ma'am.
It's alright, it's alright.
Who is it, Wilson?
- Oh! Dreadfully sorry.
Pranged the heely. Daddy will be
livid. Lorde Derwent.
Won't tell him, will'ya? God!
Oh, sorry. Frankie Derwent. How do--
- Sylvia Savage.
Wilson, What should you do?
- Send for the doctor, milady.
Send for the doctor... yes,
that's right. The doctor, Wilson.
Hurry.
Hello.
I'm Alec Nicholson.
- What hapenned?
You're jolly pretty. Are you staying?
- Dorothy! I'm so sorry, Lady Derwent.
Oh, Frankie, please.
- Hello, Frankie.
Hello.
- Dorothy, you're in the way of the doctor.
He's not really a doctor. Are you, doctor?
- Dottie!
Out, please, get out!
- It's all right.
Going anyway.
Tom?
I saw her, yes.
Now, don't you worry. I used to be
a medic during the war.
I still remember most of it.
- So, what do you do now, then?
Psichiatry, actually.
I have a clinic over the way.
Tell me ... how's that?
So, what's that, then?
- What?
Psico ... whatsit.
Looking for the truth, I suppose.
- Sounds rather terrifying.
Only if you have something to hide.
Right.
I'm going to give you...
one of these little chaps.
And you should definitely stay.
So that we can keep an eye.
There.
Pop it down.
¢Ü But now I see ¢Ü
¢Ü What one embrace can do ¢Ü
¢Ü Look at me ¢Ü
¢Ü It's got me loving you ¢Ü
¢Ü Madly ¢Ü
¢Ü That little kiss ¢Ü
¢Ü You stole ¢Ü
¢Ü Held on my heart ¢Ü
¢Ü And soul ¢Ü
By God, there you are.
I thought you had daddled.
Still here, I'm affraid.
- Smashed her car, poor darling.
Oh dear! Nothing broken, I hope.
- I don't think so.
Anyway "Dr. whatsit" said
I ought to stay, so... sorry.
Excelent diagnosis, I'd say.
Roger, Dottie ...
Poor Frankie... she's supposed
to be resting.
Though she does look better, I must say.
And you've met Roger.
A tonic for any girl,
aren't you, my darling?
Oh, do play something,
Roger? Please.
It's so wonderful to have music in the house.
Don't you think so, Frankie?
Oh, wonderful!
Frankie, will you stay to dinner tomorrow?
We always have dinner together on Thursdays.
Please, can she, mummy?
- Of course she can, my darling.
Thank you. I'd love to.
No one dresses up,
apart from Evans, of course.
Oh, God! I'm so sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
Don't worry.
Wilson will mend it.
He's a loveliest mender.
I feel a bit... I think I need to go back
to my room, for a while.
I'll take you. I'll take her.
Mummy got Roger into teach me,
rather than Tom, to play the piano.
Problem is, he's a hopeless teacher,Tommy hates
tunes and I can't get my eyes off his trousers.
Who's Evans?
- Claude, actually.
But everyone calls him Evans.
Worked for Daddy in China.
And that's Daddy.
The mighty Jack Savage.
Not so mighty now, obviously.
Ghastly death. Wriggling,
and foaming and tonguing.
Weak heart, so they say.
But I don't think so .
Don't you?
- He didn't have a heart.
You must be Tom?
Hello.
Lost something.
Sorry.
Did you find it?
- No.
This is Roland.
Touch him, if you like.
He won't byte.
- I'm a bit funny 'bout snakes.
Would you like to meet Kali?
- Kali?
Hindu Godess of death.
My Malayan pit viper.
She's deadly.
Perhaps another time.
Hello?
- Guess what.
Frankie?
- I'm here. Castle Savage.
Just thought you might like to know.
Pretended to crash the car.
Well, did crash the car actually, but
it was obviously a clever ruse,
'cause they've taken me in.
They?
- Do keep up. The Savages!
Their creepy doctor
tried to drug me.
Drug you?!
- Lady Savage is strange too.
Her son wanted me
to look at his viper.
His viper.
- Anyway,
Jack Savage died horribly,
apparently, and guess what:
he used to work
with a certain Mr. Evans.
He lives nearby. I searched
and cracked it. On my own.
What about Trent?
Trent?
Well ... obviously... he'll be
here too, I imagine.
Frankie ...
- I've got to go, sorry. Bye.
Bobby! Bobby!
Come and have some nice cake.
I'm feeling a bit better, actually,
so I thought ...
about going out.
- Marjorie, dear, I'm so sorry
about this,but a very dear friend
of mine, has taken ill in London, and
I need to visit her for a few days.
- Oh, dear!
She sounded so poorly on the phone.
And Marjorie, I wondered, London is
so hectic nowadays,
if I might possibly prevail
upon Bobby to accompany me?
Bobby?
London train!
Now you know what to do?
- Yes.
You've got the key.
You must use your whizz, now.
- I'm not sure I have any.
Oh, yes you have, my dear.
Remember the Dark Avenger!
If you ever, ever do that again...
- What have I done?
What on earth are you talking about?
We wanted to meet this young lady.
Peter Peters. How do you do?
Your little motor at the gate,
I take it.
Heading for Hereford, I believe.
- That's right.
Hello. I am Evans.
Are you alright?
You just reminded me of someone, That's all.
- Dreadfully atractive, I trust.
Dreadfully. You worked for
Lord Jack in China, I gather.
It was quite a while ago.
Cocktail, madam?
- Sure.
Who could that be? Moira?
- Hardly.
Sorry to go on. Hereford,
did you say.
Really, Peters.
- Hereford, that's right.
But your motor, I couldn't help
to notice, seemed actually...
headed away from Hereford.
Sorry.
Excuse me, Lady Derwent.
Your governess has arrived.
My "what"?
- Oh, there she is.
I'm so sorry.
Do forgive me for intruding.
I saw the car crashed
at the gate, oh dear,
but you've clearly been rescued,
thank Heavens.
You must be Lady Savage.
Do forgive me, please.
Jane Marple.
Frankie's governess. I've been
retired many years, now,
but still keep in touch,
which is so lovely.
How do you do?
- Yes...
You're cutting edge at a little time,
Miss Marple. She was about to get arrested.
Heavens!
- Comander Peters, ex-CID,
noticed that Lady Derwent's motor
was headed away from Hereford.
Don't be tiresome, Dottie!
- Nothing escapes your eagle eye, comander?
We weren't meeting in
Hereford, but in Little Thisingdan.
At the Rosebush Cafe.
Do you know it?
(the most delicious lemon curd.)
which is that way, of course.
You must've realized you've come
too far and turned around.
I did. Far too far, and
turned back on the hill to get to Little.....
Thisingdan. Yes.
- There we are, comander.
Everything's "tickety-boo" (correct).
Whatever you say, my Lady.
Would you... all excuse me. Sorry,
I just need to...
Wilson, will see to your arrangements,
Miss Marple. Wilson ...
A room next to Lady
Derwent, if it's not too much trouble.
Like old times,
isn't it, Frankie?
Of course. Wilson.
(Hotel Cattermole)
I don't need any help, you know.
- Of course you don't, dear.
Bobby is onto the Prichard connection.
Remember the key, from the car?
Bobby hes rather missed the boat, I'm affraid.
- Yes. Also ...
What?
- Downstairs. Did you feel it?
I can't quite put my finger on it,
but something's not right.
Wouldn't want to be here
without a friend.
I found this.
My room reeked of pipe.
Prichard must have been there.
(Mr. John Stansfeld Castairs)
Yes.
- I'm in the hotel. In his room.
- He was not called Prichard.
He's called Castairs.
John Castairs.
- Well done, Bobby.
And I found his diary.
He has "Savage" on the 2nd.
And something on the 8th. A code
or something .
Oh, and a photograph ...
a beautiful girl.
Moira.
- What does the code say?
What does the code say, Bobby?
"9 on the 8th, SN, year, P & P"
Another place on the map, probably.
- Solicitors.
Could be solicitors.
- Just what we're thinking.
He was dead by the 8th,
so he never got there.
And by the way, Bobby ...
It's a jungle.
- We had such excellent gardeners.
- What happened to them?
Jack got rid of them.
Just before he died.
Replaced them with those
wretching loafing boys.
Why on earth do we keep them?
- Because they're cheap.
And much prettier.
Everything's changing, isn't it?
The whole country is getting richer.
Apart from us, aparently.
The staff all gone. Tilly, the housemaid,
Eddie the kitchen girl, Gerald the poolboy...
And Florrie, of course ...
Mind you, she couldn't really've
stayed, poor little thing.
Only mrs. Perkins and Wilson left.
You keep our bodies and souls
alive somehow, don't you, my darling?
Such a struggle...
How about Roger paying his rent?
- Roger doesn't pay rent, does he?
No, he's just a pianist, isn't he?
- I'm not just a pianist, actually.
Stop, please, darlings!
- What are you, then?
Yes, what are you?
- Will you all shut up, please!!
Charming chicken, if I may say so.
It's haddock (fish), actually.
I think we all need a bit of jungle
in our lives, don't you, Miss Marple?
As long as we can find our way out.
Claude has a little jungle, don't you Claude?
Full of poisonous orquids.
Orquids? How lovely.
- They're not all poisonous, my darling.
Some of them are quite polite.
Moira!
What are you doing, darling?
You said you'd stay in bed?
I feel a bit better, I thought
I'd come over. Is that alright?
Of course, darling.
Sit by me.
It'll dry you up, perhaps.
Thank you, Wilson.
Actually, I was about to ask.
It's a long shot, but I had a friend
in these parts recently. Well,
a friend of my father's, really.
John Castairs?
More haddock, madam?
- No, thank you.
Castairs ...
- Castairs, yes!
Don't think I ...
- You remember Castairs.
Do I?
- Asking all those questions.
Of course you remember him, mother.
Asking about father's will, wasn't he?
Stop it Dorothy!
- He was here, yes, then he vanished.
Vanished?
You can blame me for that.
Told him to get packing.
Told him to his face.
- Got the point, I think.
Where would I be without Com. Peters?
I could see where he was after.
Seen it too many times.
Preying on a grieving widow.
- So, where is the money, actually?
It's been six months since dad died.
- Quiet! Quiet! Both of you!
I beg your pardon?
- Shut up!
Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
This has nothing to do with you!
Very pretty, isn't she?
- Who?
Moira.
- Suppose so.
Anyway, didn't you notice?
I just quite brilliantly discovered, if I may
say so myself, that Castairs was here.
And not only that,
they all met him.
When he was asking about the will, yes.
- But didn't you notice how they all reacted?
The children were rather upset.
- Yes, the children.
But you're missing something
much more important.
Am I, dear?
Who didn't react?
Evans, Miss Marple! He just carried on
eating his chicken.
Haddock.
- Haddock.
And I mentioned o Jack's name, just
before you arrived and he positively froze.
Oh, sorry. I'm Moira.
- Hello dear.
The doctor's wife.
We weren't introduced.
Everything went a bit crazy tonight.
My fault, I'm affraid.
Your fault?
- There... Did you hear it?
"Oh, cry! the nightingale"
"What triumph there!"
"What pain!"
Not cold, are you dear?
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
You're very lucky, Frankie, to have
such a sweet person in your life.
Your husband seems very sweet.
- Oh yes, Alex is marvellous.
So ...
- Trouble is I rely on him so much.
It's is own fault, he has
this effect, you see.
It has to do with his great, deep eyes.
Women fall for that kind of thing, don't they?
I've got no right to get upset,
it's just ...
well, he spends so much time with her
and I-- , silly, really,
end up spying on them,
and things.
Coming to dinner uninvited.
Don't know why I'm telling you this.
No, it's fine, really.
I know it's been dreadful for her.
I know she's in grief, he keeps telling me.
But honestly, why?
- Why, dear?
Jack never loved Sylvia.
Everyone knew that.
Spent all his time
chasing everybody else.
As soon as he saw a woman,
He couldn't help himself.
Addicted, Alec says.
He just kept on and on.
She knew it.
Just wouldn't admit it, that's all.
Did he chase you?
Ever since we arrived.
Did you tell anyone about this?
- Your husband?
Evans told him.
Moira, what you're doing?
- We were listening to the nightingales.
Finished at the castle, darling?
- Yes, all done.
You ought really be inside, you know?
I've got Roger's coat.
- Yes, I see.
Come along, then.
Good night, ladies.
Thank you, Moira.
Well, it's obvious, isn't it? Jack's
a monster. So,
Evans murder him. Castairs
comes along, finds out,
Evans follows him
and pushes him over the cliff.
But. But Castairs recognizes him
and said we should ask Evans.
There. Solved.
They weren't quite his words,
were they, dear?
Well, near as damn it.
Frankie, dear, you have a very sharp mind.
- Thank you.
But you must be aware of distractions.
Distractions?
Come.
I'll get another bat.
You know what happened, don't you?
- Sorry?
With Castairs. Don't you?
Come on, partner.
Wait a minute.
Just like ...
Wha-- Robert!
- Sorry to disturb you, madam,
brought madam's clothes, madam.
Perhaps you'd like to take it
to Miss Marple, please, Robert.
Mind you, where will I find
Miss Marple, madam?
I'll show you.
Come on.
Might I inquire if madam would need
some help with the bat, madam?
Missed a bit.
It's a nice moustache,..
At least I'm making an effort,
unlike some people.
At least I haven't been swanning about
at night in Knightsbridge.
Swanning about?
Com'on, Robert.
I want to see my face in it.
Pratically solved the case,
if you want to know.
We're meeting the chief suspect
this afternoon, actually
What are we doing?
Going for a spin?
We've been invited to tea,
I gather, with mr. Evans.
Great, let's all go.
- Lovely!
Your man can take us.
- Good idea. Robert!
Certainly, madam.
- He loves orquids.
A bit of a tight, I'm affraid.
- We'll manage fine.
I like your insolence, Robert.
What's this?
- Don't touch, darling!
That is discolum
septe serpentilingua.
My little serpent orquid.
- Kill you in seconds, isn't it, Claude?
Certainly would, my darling.
Where's the Pafio one?
That incredibly rare one.
Pafio Pedilium.
From China.
Crushed and imbibed by emperors.
Kept them "primmed", so to speak,
for a month.
Exhausting.
Jack's favorite.
I wouldn't have thought
Jack was a flower lover.
Jack? No.
This was just a business.
Commodities. That's all they were for him.
But not for you, are they, mr. Evans?
- No ... they're not.
They're my darling children,
if you must know. And they're all I have.
Jack was trying to get rid of them, wasn't he?
- I thought he was my friend.
But I... was... nothing!
Just a middle man!
Sorry.
Well, it's rather what you are here,
isn't it, mr. Evans?
A middle man, right between
the doctor's house and the castle,
wonderful views of each.
My God Father's, Miss Marple!
You should see what I see
in and out of that clinic.
There's an actrice,
jurister, three judges,
a politician with a strange proclivity,
an that man of "What's my line?"
And other things, Claude.
- Other things? Gosh, what?
Well, the terrible rows between
Dad and the doctor, for a start.
Moira.
- Dottie!
I don't see why we can't talk
about it. He's dead, isn't he?
She used to sit there sobbing,
little Moira, poor hunting squirrel.
She didn't know what to do.
- Now it's as bad with Alec.
You know how jealous he gets.
- She argues back.
I tell her not to...
She'll push him too far-, you know.
And one day he'll really...
Really what?
Sorry.
I don't like men-- men who...
bully women.
It's a gleam young chauffeur.
Where is it?
What have you done with the will?
- Don't know what you're talking about.
Sorry, Wilson.
You've no idea.
No idea at all.
Brothers?
That is correct, madam.
Lord Jack Savage, recently deceased.
And the first Lord, George,
his elder brother.
Milady's first husband.
Wasn't there a tragedy? I seem
to remember reading about it, in China.
A tragedy, yes, madam.
- Didn't he loose his life there?
Lord George.
- More than his life, madam.
George brought me to live here,
after we married.
Such happy days.
A time of ...
enchantment, really.
Laughter, parties, music ...
Just look at them lazing about!
So, when did you meet Jack?
Well, not until China.
Not properly, anyway.
In the court of the Emperor,
would you believe?
Pu I.
Except he wasn't
a real Emperor,
just a puppet of the Japanese.
Very handsome,
in his Saville Row's suits.
A joke, really.
He gave them China on a plate.
George could see it happening
but, he just shouted it at them.
So they killed him.
- My dear!
Jack knew it was the Japanese.
Jack knew everything.
He was very well connected.
Very charismatic and charming.
Jack took us both out. Said that,
if we didn't go now ...
Well, he'd heard rumours
what they did ...
to european girls.
I was a child myself.
Jack left you a...
very whealthy woman.
I don't know what he did
in China and I don't care.
Oh! The way they're grasping
for it...
My own children.
They sick me, frankly.
Thank you.
Dr. Nicholson!
Miss Marple!
Look, I found
a photo of your wife.
Where did you find that?
Oh, so beautiful here!
Perfect place to heal the mind.
You must have been thrilled
when Lord Jack offered it to you.
That was Moira, actually.
She had already met Jack.
And charmed him completely,
I'm sure.
I am not surprised
you fell in love with her.
Yes. Anyway ...
- Kuala Nerang. That's in Malaya, isn't it?
It looks like a hospital.
That's right.
She was my nurse, actually.
I went as a psychiatrist,
but they needed doctors.
Well I was still pretty hoarse ...
- You could tie a bandage.
Exactly.
- Wield a syringe.
Right. So, Moira and I...
- Fell in love. How romantic!
Is that Amber Flash ou Amber Queen?
Sorry?
- May I?
Amber Queen, I think.
It's quite intoxicating, isn't it?
Oh. Please.
¢Ü ¢Ü
¢Ü Do you recall ¢Ü
¢Ü When love was all... ¢Ü
¢Ü ... and we were seventeen ¢Ü
So, how did you...
- Wind up here?
Well, I was playing in a club in Soho,
actually. Pretty much broke.
One day, Alec and Moira walk in,
out of the blue.
Alec said he knew this
milionare who's absolutely loaded...
And wife wants their kids
to learn the piano.
And I could just live there and just ...
- Just what, Roger?
Just wait for the money.
That's what she said? Did she?
But I've got a surprise
for you, Roger.
I've seen the will and if you think
think you'll get ...
Well, I've... I've seen the will,
if you think you'll getting any,
if you think, well,
I've got certain means.
- How dare you?
How dare you? Did you just
accuse me of... How...?
Is that what you think?
That bastard!
I-- I'm sorry, Frankie.
You've got to get out.
- What?
You heard the poison he let out.
There are mean things here, Frankie.
You've got to leave.
Sorry.
Bugger! Sorry ...
You've just got to get out.
That's all.
But just say
you'll see me again.
But not here.
Somewhere different.
Somewhere safe.
Last Will
of Jack Savage
"Quang Ho Orphanage", China.
Robert!
Robert?
I know you're there!
Robert!
Wait, it's alright!
Wait!
- Don't, please!
It's alright.
- I thought you were...
Aah!
- Can you move it?
Thank you.
You're probably wondering what I'm doing?
- No, I ...
They all say "poor little Moira". As if
I don't know what's going on, as if I'm a child.
I know what's going on.
Why don't he just tell me he doesn't love her,
that he just wants her money.
But he doesn't love me.
He doesn't even notice me.
I think you're the most noticeable
person I've ever noticed.
I've got to get back.
Here.
I'm Moira, by the way.
- I know.
Please.
"All to the Wight Isle,
except Florrie".
May I?
So ...
Cracked, don't you think?
Sorry?
- The doctor.
Evans, actually.
- No, actually ...
Look, I've been in this case
three whole days,
while you've been
chasing Moira around.
Chasing Moira?
- And I'm positively sure it was Evans.
Evans, Evans, Evans ...
Help!
I don't know why you're looking
so smug. He still did it.
Commander, would you mind terribly
reading the note again, please?
Certainly, Lady Derwent.
"My life of sin
is no longer bearable."
"Goodbye, dear Sylvia. Claude."
- May I, commander?
Identical handwriting, you see?
Not quite identical, actually.
Look at the "L's".
Very inconsistent looping.
I think you'd also have inconsistent
looping, young man,
if you were about to
stuff yourself with orquids.
Each flower was neatly decapitaded.
Why did you do such a cold and
cruel thing to - what did he call them?
"His darling children."
If I might be able to ramble for a
brief moment in the psychiatrist domain--
I think that you should order
an immediate post-mortem, commander.
Madame, Lady Savage has been
stressed enough by recent ...
A cruel and unnecessary death
occurred, commander.
I do think one should be utterly
certain of the circumstances
before the veil is finally drawn,
don't you?
Evans kills Jack, then pushes
Castairs over the cliff, then tries
to run you over and tops himself.
It's blindingly obvious.
They silenced before we could ask him.
- What?
But Castairs was silenced when he was pushed
over the cliff, Evans wasn't the killer.
What?
- "Why didn't they ask Evans?"
We know his last words, "ask Evans".
Obviously, Evans knew something.
Interesting. Our Mr. Trent, or
whoever called himself Mr. Trent,
knew Carstairs' last words
as well, of course.
Yes, we wrote Trent, but
Trent is Evans, and Evans is dead.
What?
- I saw him.
What did you see, dear?
- Nothing.
What did you see, Bobby?
- I simply saw Roger, heading to
Evans' house, at exactly the same time--
It doesn't mean he was going to poison him
with half of his bloody orquids.
Anyway, last night you thought it was
the doctor. I can't keep up with you!
Roger I'm going to ask you a question,
and I'll just do it so that we know where we are.
You were seen leaving
the castle and heading towards
Evans' house, last night,
just before he died.
I wasn't going to Evans' house.
- Well, where were you going?
To the doctor's, actually.
- Why, Roger?
Why, Roger?
'cause I was feeling unwell.
You're seeing Moira.
- Don't be ridiculous.
You were. You're seeing Moira.
- Dottie!
You were, weren't you? You are
having an affair, aren't you?
Are you two having an affair?
- Alright, yes!
Yes ... Yes, we are.
We were.
But not anymore.
You actually been ...
- Dottie!
Who saw me?
- I did.
The bloody chauffeur?
- Not a chauffeur, actually!
I am actually ...
Lady Derwent's friend.
And we are investigating the
murder of John Castairs!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I will ask you to... kindly
remain in the premisses.
Not now, Peters.
- Very good, milady.
Well, they all know now!
- He called me a chauffeur!
You are a chauffeur!
- I'm not a chauffeur!
Why must you be so bloody obnoxious?
- I'm sorry. I...
Oh,you're obviously delighted about Roger,
proved he's a lousy cheater. Well done!
Still, Moira is not as innocent as she looks.
- You don't even know her!
I think we should keep our voices down.
- What's the point? Everything's blown now!
Wilson!
- Sorry, mr. Wilson, this is important.
Lady Savage mustn't be disturbed!
Oh, my God!
As I thought.
- Hello, Jane.
Mommy!
What're you doing?
- Please, miss. Don't come in.
Hello Dottie, darling.
I'm so sorry, my darling.
What's the matter, mommy? Why are
you talking like that? What's the matter with her?
You see, Dorothy, my dear. She's not
having an affair with the doctor.
There's an affair with Alec...
He's obsessed with Moira.
He's just delivering your supplies,
isn't he, Lady Savage?
And then it's up to you,
isn't it, Mr. Wilson?
Quite an expert,
after all these years.
Disgusting! You're disgusting, Wilson!
He had to, my darling.
He had to ... It was the ...
It was the what?
- The pain.
She said it was the pain.
The pain.
If you see Frankie would you tell her
that it is over between me and Moira ...
No more errands, sorry.
Does Nicholson know about you two?
No, he can't. At least I don't think he can.
Where's she now?
- She's in the house.
But Nicholson won't let me in,
he's got a patient.
She's in the house with the doctor?
- Yes.
All right.
- Well, I'm coming too.
Where's Moira, Doctor?
- You're the bloody chauffeur!
I'm not a chauffeur!
- Where is she, Alec?
I have a patient here, in a very delicate state.
This is the 1st time she's spoken in 3 months.
Any sound noise, any noise at all,
any schock, and all my work will be
absolutely wasted. So, just go away!!
Go away now, please, very quietly now,
please. If you don't ...
- Don't loose your temper with me, Alec!
I'm not loosing my bloody temper!
Right. Com'on.
Commander!
- Ah! The chauffeur detective.
- I am not ...
- You got to listen to this, Peters.
- I don't think so, sir.
I am in charge of this investigation now.
If you care to follow me, please.
Ah, Miss Marple, just in time.
I'm now able to reveal that a substance
of an highly alien and toxic nature
has been located in Mr. Evans' bloodstream.
Deadly snake venom.
You'd like to make your mark,
wouldn't you, young man?
For once, in your lonely,
clustered life.
I know! How about extracting the venom
from a Malayan pit viper,
and poison an old
flower lover.
Commander, you don't seem to realize...
- Quiet, please, sir!
That would make a splash
in the world, wouldn't it?
The snake murderer
of Castle Savage.
The black cap. The march
to the scaffold.
You could join the gallery
of famous murderers, couldn't you, sir?
Please, commander!
Frankie! Miss Marple!
He didn't do it! Tell them, Tom.
I know he didn't.
Who was it, then?
Was it you, miss?
No, it wasn't me!
- I know it wasn't.
It wasn't Tom either.
Because I happen to know that extracting
the snake venom of a highly venomous sake
requires certain implements
and profissional expertise.
That's what we've been trying...
- Will you let me please finish, thank you, sir!
Now...
one final question, young man.
How did you first come by
this highly venomous snake?
- It was a gift.
Who from, sir?
- From Dr. Nicholson.
Well, that's what I was trying to ...
I wasn't in the "Flying Squad"
for 40 years for nothing, Miss Marple.
I can see that, Commander.
She can be in bloody Timbuktu, for all I know!
- Where is she?
Oh, just go away!
God, Bobby!
Moira? Moira!
Moira, are you there?
Where are you?
Mrs. Nicholson!
Alec Mathew Nicholson,
I'm arresting you on suspicion of
mudering Claude Arthur Evans.
It can't be him! It wasn't him!
It wasn't...
Tom, I need to see the will.
The one mr. Castairs gave you.
He said he'd come back,
but he didn't.
Yes, I know.
There's something wrong with it, isn't there?
That's why he told you to keep it.
Thank you, Tom.
Last will and test ...
- He changed it!
Left everything to a bloddy
orphanage, he hated children.
Why a bloody orphanage in China?
- And the day before he died.
That's not his solicitor. Manning,
was his solicitor.
A mr. Snape.
And the witnesses. G. Sparks, T. Wilkins?
- Never heard of them.
Didn't want Dorothy and me
witnessing anything, obviously.
That's why he sent us away.
- To the Isle of Wight, wasn't it?
Could have asked Florrie.
Why didn't they ask her?
Florrie?
- The nursemaid. She could have
witnessed it.
Florrie didn't go with you?
- Had to stay here to give him
his heart drugs.
He just wanted to harass her.
- Well, poor Florrie.
Lord Jack fired the gardeners
while you away on the Isle of Wight.
You came home to new gardeners,
Mr Sparks and Mr Wilkins, isn't that right?
Yes, that's right.
- And Lorde Jack already dead?
Yes. Now, I re--
- One more question, Mr. Wilson, please.
How were you informed of your
trip to the Wight hotel?
A scribbled note, as usual,
saying that everything was arranged,
and to get everybody out of his sight.
That's how he did things.
Not like his brother, Lord George.
I- I really don't recall.
- Oh, I think you do.
They were different times, weren't they.
What did she call them? A time of enchantment...
Of music, of laughter ...
That what George rode
her life, wasn't it?
When they married.
And then, brother Jack leaped in.
It is one of the great human misteries.
Why are we so prepared to destroy
all that is good and decent,
all for a pair of dark eyes?
Then the world intruded,
didn't it, Lady Savage?
China.
- China ...
Jack ...
Then the rules no longer applied.
You can't protect her now,
Mr. Wilson, from the memories.
They're all coming back,
aren't they, my dear?
You knew, didn't you? You knew
Jack had his brother murdered.
But it was too much to bare,
wasn't it?
You you'd lost the man
who really loved you.
Knew it in your soul.
You thought you coud forget, didn't you?
- Forget ...
So much to forget...
- Please ...
Is that why you couldn't
love your children?
Because you couldn't forget.
Because of the grief.
Is that why you could never be
a real mother to them?
They're like... orphans, aren't they?
- No, please!
Miss Marple, I beg you.
Your heart goes out to them, doesn't it,
Wilson? To poor Tom and Dorothy.
Is it them?
Is it, Wilson?
Or is it ...?
Oh! You're going?
- Yes.
Well, I just wanted to say--
- What?
She's gone now... out of my life.
Lucky you.
Can I help--
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
Frankie ...
What?
Wait for me.
There's just one thing
I got to do first.
It's Sylvia's birthday, actually.
Tomorrow.
I feel like I got to go, really. After,
you know, everything, she's gone through.
Then I'll be free.
And then we can be together.
Moira! Poor darling!
I had no idea about
Alec. So dreadful!
Thank goodness for this young man.
Yes, thank goodness.
You're going away?
- To France, yes.
But it's your birthday tomorrow!
- I'd rather forget about it, anyway.
But you alway do your birthday.
- Oh, little face.
Don't worry about my life.
You've got your own back now,
haven't you?
I hope so.
Just ...
Well, wanted to thank you.
Ah, well ...
- Don't forget me.
Flat as well.
- Both flat.
You were right about the doctor.
You did all the work.
- We both did a little work.
Did you make up with Roger?
- He's asked me to wait.
Wait?
- 'til after Sylvia's birthday.
I wouldn't ask you to wait.
Wouldn't you?
Anyway, good luck!
- Thanks.
Good luck with Moira.
What?
- She mentioned it too.
Who?
- Moira.
Mentioned what?
- Sylvia's birthday.
Hello?
Who is that?
Moira, thank goodness!
- Hello, darling.
We've come to celebrate.
But it's not my birthday 'til tomorrow!
Still don't know who we are,
do you?
My God!
Please!
Mummy!
You've left us for dead,
for dear uncle Jack, but we've come back.
Hello, mummy.
We're Alice and Michael, darling.
We've come home.
Michael was luckier than me. Found
a nice English family,who've put him in a home.
But I was not so lucky, had to stay to
entertain the soldiers.
You know what the made her do?
Do you have any idea? D'you have any idea?
Not quite what you're used to,
I'm affraid.
This is mixed with
snake venom.
The snake I got Alec to give
Tom for his birthday.
Michael.
Wilson!
I heard every word, Miss Alice.
Put it down, please!
Well, we're all here...
Why didn't you go when you could go?
I did mean it, Frankie. I do mean it.
Everything I said, I- I re--...
- Oh, shut up, Michael!
She's a split second from the needle.
Put the gun down, Charles.
Well, that was a waste of time, wasn't it?
Are we ready?
Then I'll begin. Michael.
Is that all you're going to do, dear?
Just kill her?
Don't you want her to know
how you did it, how you've exquisitely
planned this moment, all these years?
I'm sure, once the venom enters her
bloodstream, she'll be in far too much in agony
to take much of it in.
- You seem to know all about it, Miss Marple.
I just observe, dear.
- Perhaps you'll tell what you've observed
and I'll tell you if you're right?
- Uh, would you mind putting the needle down?
Please, dear, the sight of a needle,
it really makes quite giddy.
Still dread the dentist, always
have, just a coward. If you wouln't mind.
Thank you so much. Well ...
For a start, he had no idea,
had he, Dr. Nicholson?
That he was passing on
such fatal knowledge.
Men always like answering girl's questions,
make them feel superior.
How the venom of the malayan pit viper,
for example, can replicate
the symptoms of a critical cardiac failure,
isn't that what it's called?
Poor Jack.
He must have been beside himself,
with joy, that evening,
when you dropped around saying that
you'd changed your mind about his offer.
Jack.
Poisoning Jack was, one can say,
child's play to you.
But now, the real drama began.
Your next job was to disguise
yourself, wasn't it, Roger?
Michael.
- So sorry. Michael.
So good at mimicry and disguises.
I'm sure you were an excelent Mr. Trent,
at the inquest about your "cousin",
Mr. Castairs. You really
should've been an actor.
And an excellent forger, too.
At least of suicide notes.
And the note to Mr. Wilson,
telling him to take Lady Savage
and her family to the Isle of Wight.
And the note to Florrie, the nursemaid,
telling her to take the afternoon off,
and, by the way, would she call out
the gardeners, before she went?
That is, the new gardeners, of course.
The old ones had been fired, hadn't they?
They were needed to witness a will...
Lorde Jack Savage's new will.
Am I right so far?
Go on.
- So, then a solicitor arrived,
not the usual solicitor, no.
A new solicitor, a Mr. Snape.
Who let them in, I wonder?
The solicitors and the new gardeners?
Well, it should have been Florrie, of course,
because it was the one person left in the house,
but she'd been given the afternoon off,
so, clearly,
a brand new nursemaid
let them in.
And the reason why nobody who
knew him could be there,
was because the Jack that Roger created
had just made a
rather drastic change to his will.
Not that the new gardeners would've cared.
Hadn't even bothered to wash their hands!
Jack's money was left to the
Quang Ho Orphanage, in Xangai.
You won't see a penny,
will you, Lady Savage?
But that's all right, isn't it?
It's a small price to pay.
All his foul, filthy money.
I was happy he was leaving it
to the little lost children of China.
I want all the children in all
the world to have all the money.
I want... all the children...
in all the world,
to smile.
And take away this pain.
- You think that takes you off the hook?
You really think that your
pathetic guilt...
Sorry, I hadn't quite
finished. May I? The story?
The moment it all changes,
what do they call it... the twist?
Go on!
- Well,it was all getting so well,wasn't it?
You killed Jack,
organised all the money,
all that was left was, to prepare
to this final moment.
And then, oh dear!
Mr. Castairs arrived.
Jack's old "compadre". You
had not reckoned with him, had you?
I can't believe that any of you've taken
this will seriously.
And Sylvia, will you contest the will?
You know as well as I do, that' what...
He knew something was wrong,
travelled all the way from China to investigate.
And he wouldn't let it go, like a
terrier, Mr. Carstairs. So many questions.
But I showed him the will.
I wouldn't get a penny.
I told him I didn't care.
Give it to the orphanage.
Give it to the children.
But he did care.
He knew it was a forgery,
because he knew Jack.
Oh, he was close, so very close. Then,
he went on that last fatal journey.
But you never thought to ask
why he was there, did you?
So, why was he there?
- Looking for Evans, of course.
But Evans was here.
- Yes, indeed, Claude Evans was here.
You killed him to frame him,
poor man.
But there's another Evans, you see?
You still don't know that, do you?
What other Evans?
- He was so close...
He just couldn't answer that final
question: Why? Why?
Why didn't they ask Evans?
Why didn't they ask Evans what?
- To witness the will, of course.
Why to go through all that trouble of
sacking and hiring and impersonating,
- When all they had to do was ask Evans?
- What Evans? Who's this man Evans?
Ah, you see, now... that's the mistake.
It is, it is such an easy thing to do.
Assuming that Evans was a man,
whereas all along it was a woman.
A young woman.
A nursemaid, in fact.
Florrie Evans.
- So why couldn't they ask her, Miss Marple?
Because, my dear, she would have
recognised Roger instantly.
But they needed her there, she had
to be there to discover Jack.
To witness the sudden onset of his
so called illness.
Darling...
Do it.
Go on.
Do it, please!
No.
- I want to die. Do it, darling.
Or ... I know ...
Let me have. Give it to me.
I'll do it. Wilson and I, we'll do it.
Listen, Wilson, Wilson's very good.
Plenty of pratice.
For God's sake, get on with it,
get it over with. Go on!
- Moira.
- Alice! I'm Alice!
Tom, go! Do something!
Go on! Take the gun!
Tom!
I'm so sorry, Miss Alice.
What I still don't get is why was
Castairs looking for Evans here?
Oh, haven't I explained that bit?
I'm so sorry.
Mrs. Roberts!
- Oh, more cake, is it?
May one call you Florrie?
Florence, actually madam.
Florrie was my last job.
When you were Evans?
- That's right, it's correct, madam.
Nursemaid to Sir Jack Savage?
- Yes. I was...
Not wishing to speak ill of the dead,
randy begger. If you take my meaning.
Oh, quite.
- At least you're happy now?
Yes, indeed . Married to
Mr. Roberts now.
Treats me like I'm royal
princess Margaret, if you pardon my French.
That's all we can ask, isn't it?
Someone who treats you right.
Like there's diamond on your souls.
Lady Derwent, what an honor!
Roberts, this is not the correct china.
- Ah, it's not Roberts, mother.
It's Florence.
- I beg your pardon?
Cliff walk, anyone?
Hungarian subtitles
Krassimir Sevova
Translation & resynch
titta for Addic7ed.com